# **Anastasiya Yaskevich**

# React Native Developer

Cracow, Poland anastasia.yaskevich@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

I am a mobile developer with 3-year experience in React Native and 8 years in software engineering in total. I've worked with various tools and technologies, both as solo developer and in a team. My English level is Upper Intermediate. I participate in Women In Tech Belarus as a mentor.

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2011 — 06/2016

# **Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics**

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Systems and Networks. Got specialization in Sotfware for Information Technologies.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

12/2019 — 12/2022

#### **React Native Developer at Loóna**

Created an Android app for existing React Native iOS app with Unity, which included implementing native modules and setting up a CI workflow. Also implemented features on React side. Did a side project of creating a website in React from scratch by myself, that included infrastructure setup. Done some infrastructural improvements, e.g. reducing repository size from 500+GB to 7GB. Took part in an ongoing JavaScript to TypeScript migration as well as increasing Unit test coverage. Participated in interviewing candidates for both mobile and frontend teams.

06/2019 — 12/2019

#### Android Developer at SolbegSoft

Development of an SDK for a social video mobile application from scratch. Refactoring of the main app. Used Kotlin, MVICore, Clean Architecture, Retrofit, RxJava 2, Toothpick.

11/2018 — 03/2019

#### Android Developer at iFuture

Development and refactoring of a betting mobile application. Used Kotlin, MVI, Clean Architecture, Retrofit, RxJava 2, Dagger 2, JUnit and Mockito. Optimized performance of a list with complex components.

03/2018 — 11/2018

#### **Android Developer at iFuture**

Development and refactoring of a client mobile application. Used Kotlin, Retrofit, Room, RxJava 2, Dagger 2, MVP, Clean Architecture. Took part in implementation of Form Decorator (transformed JSON of field appearance description into UI) and implemented demo app.

Development and refactoring of a betting mobile web application in JavaScript, React.js and Redux. Support of Android wrapper app in Crosswalk.

## 11/2015 — 07/2016 Groovy Developer at iFuture

Development and refactoring of a large betting web application and a CMS. Used Groovy & Grails, MySQL, CoffeeScript, AngularJS, Redis.

# 02/2015 — 11/2015 Junior Groovy Developer at REID Consulting

Creating small web apps including frontend part from scratch. Used Groovy & Grails and Jenkins as CI. Worked by myself but had code review by a mentor.